Here's the thing that people forget because the way that we learn history is very siloed when in actuality these things were happening in a very close sequential time frame.
Civil Rights Act of 1964, Voting Rights Act. So Malcolm X is murdered, assassinated, 1963, and so is Kennedy. 1964, Civil Rights Act. 1965, Voting Rights Act. 1967, Martin Luther King. 1968, no, 1968, Martin Luther King. 1968, riots all over. 1968, Housing Rights Act, right?
So these are three over the course of a short, short span of time. You're seeing these, these legislative efforts, so to speak, to say, OK, blacks, we're going to we're going to be OK with you. You're going to get a damn. Right.
Then we also at the same time have the college students demanding ethnic studies and a presence in academia. So this is happening in the 60s.
Then we go into Vietnam. Simultaneously, we have the black arts movement. We have the black power movement. We have all these cultural movements of let's take back our identity.
This is happening in a very short amount of time.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And they're like, these niggas is getting too hype.
So we're going to give them heroin in Vietnam.
For sure.
Frank White's going to give heroin in New York.
And so you have a whole generation that was hooked on heroin in the late 70s.
And then they kept it going with crack.
And after all of that pain of the 60s and all these assassinations and this war and losing all of these people, there's a welcome.
There's a fatigue and a welcome that drugs, I think, also brings.
And let's not also forget, drugs did not really become deadly in the way that we know it to be until really the 80s.
Like, folks was definitely doing coke and living their best lives.
There should be more focus on what you just said.
There should be more focus on the sequence of events.
If we started like Trayvon 2014, and for the average millennial adult, it's just like Trayvon, Mike Brown.
Listen, listen, listen, listen, correct, correct, correct, pandemic, yes, yes.
Like, first Trump presidency, pandemic, second Trump presidency, and with social media, it's quite literally like, the thing that hit me yesterday, that has hit me several times before, is like, you never fucking know what you're going to wake up to with these damn phones.